E-mail: t.g.paskhalis@lse.ac.uk
February 4, 2019

Web: tom.paskhal.is

10014015 1, 2010

I am a computational political scientist, specialising in political communication, comparative politics, quantitative methods and text analysis.

EDUCATION

SUMMARY

PhD, Social Research Methods

2015 - 2019 (expected)

London School of Economics and Political Science, London, UK

Dissertation title: "Essays in Political Text: New Actors, New Data, New Challenges." Supervisors: Kenneth Benoit, Benjamin Lauderdale

Visiting Scholar, Center for Data Science

2018

New York University, New York, US

MSc (with Distinction), Social Research Methods

2013 - 2014

London School of Economics and Political Science, London, UK

BA, Political Psychology

2007 - 2012

St Petersburg State University, St Petersburg, Russia

UNDER REVIEW

Denisa Kostovicova, **Tom Paskhalis** "Gendered Peace-building: Women's Presence and Voice in Transitional Justice."

Denisa Kostovicova, Rachel Kerr, Ivor Sokolic, Tiffany Fairey, Henry Redwood, Jelena Subotic, **Tom Paskhalis** "Data in Transitional Justice: The Digital Turn, Research Prospects and Ethical Dilemmas."

WORKING PAPERS

Tom Paskhalis, Christian Müller "The Least Unclear Language: How Avoiding Negatives Produces Positive Understanding."

WORK IN PROGRESS

Tom Paskhalis "Interest Group Access to the Government: Who Gets It?"

Tom Paskhalis "Record Linkage with Text: Matching Interest Groups in the UK."

Tom Paskhalis "Interest Group Strategies in the Digital Era: Lobbying and Social Media."

Denisa Kostovicova, Ivor Sokolic, **Tom Paskhalis** "Emotion Shift and Transitional Justice: A Micro- and Macro-level Effects in Justice Debates in the Balkans."

Krisztián Pósch, **Tom Paskhalis** "'A word after a word after a word is power' Automating Manipulation Checks for Experiments with Textual Responses."

SOFTWARE

tabulizer: R Bindings for PDF Table Extractor Library 'Tabula'. CRAN GitHub RgovUK: R Package for Downloading Data from Gov.UK Publications. GitHub

AWARDS & GRANTS

Text as Data Conference travel grant, 2018

Santander Travel Fund [NYU research visit], 2018

Clifford C. Clogg scholarship [ICPSR fees waiver], 2017

ESRC Data Analysis Workshop bursary, 2016

LSE Postgraduate Travel Fund, 2016, 2017, 2018

LSE PhD studentship, 2015-2019

ADDITIONAL TRAINING

ICPSR Summer Program, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, US 2017

Courses taken: Bayesian Modelling for Social Sciences, Network Analysis

ESRC Advanced Training Initiative, Nottingham Trent University, Nottingham, UK 2016

Courses taken: Nonlinear and Latent Variable Models, Introduction to Advanced Bayesian Multilevel Modelling

Mathematics for Information Systems 2011 - 2013

Faculty of Mathematics and Mechanics, St Petersburg State University, St Petersburg, Russia

ECPR Summer School, University of Ljubljana, Ljubljana, Slovenia 2011

Courses taken: Quantitative Text Analysis

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Researcher, AHRC Art & Reconciliation, KCL/LSE	2017 - 2019
Research Assistant, Denisa Kostovicova, LSE	2016 -
Research Assistant, Tomila Lankina, LSE	2015
Research Assistant, Alexander Herzog & Maja Kluger Rasmussen, LSE	2014

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Instructor, MY491 Introduction to R workshop (MSc/PhD)	2018/19
Instructor, Text Analysis in R workshop (MSc/PhD)	2018/19
Teaching Assistant, MY470 Computer Programming (MSc/PhD)	2018/19
Teaching Assistant, MY452 Applied Regression Analysis (MSc/PhD)	2017/18
Teaching Assistant, MY451 Introduction to Quantitative Analysis (MSc/PhD)	2016/17, 17/18
Teaching Assistant, MY459 Quantitative Text Analysis (MSc/PhD)	2015/16
LSE	,

Teaching Assistant, SC104 Automated Collection of Web and Social Data	2018
Teaching Assistant, SC105 Big Data Analysis in the Social Sciences	2018
ECPR Summer School, Central European University, Budapest, Hungary	

Methods Surgery, LSE 2015 - 2018

NON-ACADEMIC EXPERIENCE

Data Science Intern
YPlan, London, UK

CONFERENCE PARTICIPATION

(P = presenter, D = discussant)

EPSA, Belfast, UK	2019 (P, scheduled)
CEEISA-ISA, Belgrade, Serbia	2019 (P, scheduled)
PSA Political Methodology Group Annual Conference, Warwick, UK	2019 (P)
Text as Data, Seattle, US	2018
Conflict Research Society, Birmingham, UK	2018 (P)

APSA, Boston, US EPSA, Vienna, Austria Manifesto Corpus Conference, Berlin, Germany PSA Political Methodology Group Annual Conference, Essex, UK APSA, San Francisco, US EPSA, Milan, Italy BISA, Brighton, UK LSE Applied Text Analysis Conference, London, UK ECPR Standing Group on Interest Groups, Copenhagen, Denmark	2018 (P) 2018 (P) 2018 (P) 2018 (P) 2017 (P) 2017 (P) 2017 (P,D) 2016 (P)
INVITED TALKS	2010
"Interest Group Access to the Government: Who Gets It?" Political Behaviour Group, LSE, London, UK	2019
"Gender, Justice and Deliberation: Women's Voice in Post-Conflict Reconciliation" Conflict Research Group, LSE, London, UK	2018
"Women Deliberators and Transitional Justice: What Kind of Voice?" Centre for Women, Peace and Security, LSE, London, UK	2017
"Kak rabotaet sovremenny kontent-analiz: Razbor partiinych programm" (How Modern Content Analysis Works: Analysis of Party Programmes) European University, St Petersburg, Russia	2011

COMPUTER SKILLS

Statistics: R, Stata, SPSS, Stan, JAGS Programming Languages: R, Python, bash

Miscellaneous: git, LATEX, MySQL, AWS/OpenStack, Qt/PyQt, REST API

LANGUAGES

English (proficient), Russian (native), Greek (advanced), German (basic)

PROFESSIONAL MEMBERSHIP

American Political Science Association European Political Science Association

EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Co-founder and cordinator (2018/19) of the Quantitative Methods Reading Group Elected Secretary of the LSESU Methodology Society

REFERENCES

Kenneth Benoit, Professor of Quantitative Social Research Methods, Department of Methodology, London School of Economics and Political Science, email: k.r.benoit@lse.ac.uk

Benjamin Lauderdale, Professor of Political Science, Department of Political Science, University College London, email: b.lauderdale@ucl.ac.uk